# Piper Macke

piper.macke@gmail.com 859-750-4250 Washington, District of Columbia

### Summary

Self-motivated Data Science student and former Division One athlete with an extremely developed work ethic and many years of experience in team leadership roles, currently expanding knowledge of various programming languages, data visualization tools, and methods of statistical analysis

#### **Technical Skills**

- Proficiency in programming with RStudio
- · Experience with Python, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Github, Posit Cloud
- · Ability to clean, visualize, and present real-world data
- Experience with introductory machine learning concepts
  - clustering, decision trees, calculating entropy, building confusion matrices
- Usage of Python libraries NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas
- Quarto Website Development
- Data Wrangling and Visualization with R and Python

#### Soft Skills

- · Analytics and problem-solving
- · Fast, receptive learner
- · Exceptional work ethic
- Strong ability to work independently

#### Education

## The George Washington University

2020-2024

Bachelor of Science in Data Science • Washington, D.C. • 3.69 GPA

- Presidential Academic Scholarship recipient
- Dean's List: Columbian College and Arts and Sciences
- Relevant coursework: Intro to Programming with Python, Data Science for All, Intro to Web Software Development, Data Visualization, Data Mining, Linear Algebra

## Highlands High School

2016-2020

Fort Thomas, Kentucky • 4.4 GPA

- Top 10% of class
- National Honor Society, National English Honor Society, Tri-M Music Honor Society, Highlands Chamber Orchestra
- · Led varsity basketball and softball teams to multiple district and regional championships

## Professional Experience

## U.S. House of Representatives | Undergraduate Fellow

06/2023 - 08/2023

- Reviewed and summarized hearings, interviews, and investigations led by the Select Subcommittee on the Coronavirus Pandemic
- Attended and contributed to discussions with members of Congress, panels comprised of Chiefs of Staff, and full committee briefings and meetings
- · Cleaned and edited hearing transcripts, guidances, and memorandums

## Macke Law Office | Legal Intern

05/2020 - 08/2020

- · Compiled, reviewed, and edited legal documents and data
- Optimized spreadsheet evaluations working with Microsoft Excel
- · Assisted in client contact with inventors

# Athletics and Leadership Division One Women's Basketball Player

# 2020-2023

The George Washington University • Washington, D.C.

• Balanced 20-40 weekly hours alongside several travel days a month of athletic obligations in addition to academics

- Scheduled regular meetings with coaches to analyze personal weaknesses and earn playing time as a walk-on
- Influenced prospective student-athletes by leading campus tours and prioritizing their well-being throughout the entirety of their visit
- Member of LEAPP (Leadership Excellence: Acquire, Practice, Perform) alongside other specially chosen university athletes for their leadership ability